Richard Rodgers Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Show Music (Box 1-18, Box 22-45)
  - Manuscripts (Box 1-18)
    - I Remember Mama (1979) lyrics by Martin Charnin and Raymond Jessel
      - Uncle Chris!, Holograph lead sheet in pencil; [2] p.; Typed lyric sheet; 2 p.; Lyric by Raymond Jessel (Box-folder 8/16)
      - We're staying here, Holograph lead sheet in pencil and photocopy; [1] p. each; Laid in: Typed lyric sheets (2); 2 p. each; Lyric by Martin Charnin; Note: included is a 2 p. typed letter from Rita Chambers to Mrs. Rodgers, indicating that this song was not used in I Remember Mama, but planned to be used for the Actors' Fund (Box-folder 8/17)
      - Dow'ry, Holograph lead sheet in pencil; [1] p.; Uniform title: What kind of man (Box-folder 8/18)
      - What kind of man, Typed lyric sheet; [1] p. (Box-folder 8/18)
      - When?, Holograph lead sheet in pencil; [1] p.; Typed lyric sheet; [1] p.; Lyric by Martin Charnin (Box-folder 8/19)
      - [Where we came from], Typed lyric sheet; [1] p.; Lyric by Raymond Jessel (Box-folder 8/20)
      - We don't wanna go back, Holograph lead sheet in pencil; [1] p.; Uniform title: Where we came from (Box-folder 8/20)
      - Women without men, Holograph lead sheet in pencil; [1] p.; Lyrics by Martin Charnin; Laid in: typed lyric sheet; [1] p.; Note: written for, but unused in I Remember Mama (Box-folder 8/21)
      - A writer writes at night see: [Lyric sheets for I Remember Mama]
      - You could not please me more, Holograph lead sheet in pencil; [1] p.; Typed lyric sheet; [1] p.; Lyric by Martin Charnin (Box-folder 8/22)
      - [Lyric sheets for I Remember Mama], Typed lyric sheets; [12] p. total; Lyrics by Martin Charnin; Includes: A fam'ly we will be Mama always makes it better An old city boy at heart Such good fun A writer writes at night (Box-folder 8/23)
      - [Letter from Martin Charnin to R. Rodgers], Holograph letter in ink, dated Dec. 25, '77; [1] p.; Note: attached are typed lyric sheets for "The day Lars Gundersen died," "He's a most disagreeable man," "Time," and "You could not please me more" (Box-folder 8/24)
      - [Song listings with notes]: Typed and photocopied lists of used and unused songs; [6] p. (Box-folder 8/25)
      - [I Remember Mama playbills]: Playbills (2) from the Majestic Theatre, June and August, 1979 (Box-folder 8/26)
      - [I Remember Mama picture card]: Picture card featuring Liv Ullmann (Box-folder 8/26)
    - I'd Rather Be Right (1937) lyrics by Lorenz Hart
      - Beauty sequence: [Here he is!], Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 5 p. (Box-folder 8/27)
      - Ev'rybody loves you See also: [Sketches for Fools for Scandal], Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [3] p. (Box-folder 8/28)
      - Have you met Miss Jones?, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [3] p. (Box-folder 8/29)
      - His chances are not worth a penny see: [Sketches for I'd Rather Be Right]
      - A homogeneous cabinet see: [Sketches for I'd Rather Be Right]
      - I'd rather be right [versions 1 & 2] see: [Sketches for I'd Rather Be Right]
      - Labor is the thing See also: [Sketches for I Married an Angel], Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 6 p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet; [1] p. (Box-folder 8/30)
      - Not so innocent fun, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 6 p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet with crossed out title "Nine young girls and nine old men" (Box-folder 8/31)
      - Sweet sixty-five see: [Sketches for I'd Rather Be Right]
      - Take and take and take, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [4] p. (Box-folder 8/32)
      - A treaty, my sweetie, with you see: [Sketches for I'd Rather Be Right]
      - We're going to balance the budget, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [3] p. (Box-folder 8/33)
      - [Sketches for I'd Rather Be Right], Holograph sketches in pencil; [8] p.; Includes: p. [1]: "[A homogeneous] cabinet" p. [2]: "[A homogeneous] cabinet" p. [3]: "Verse Everybody loves you," "[Sweet sixty-five],""[Sweet sixty-five]: Verse 40 years" p. [5]: "[A homogeneous cabinet]: Cab 2," "[Take and take and take]," "Verse Lovely lady," "[Beauty sequence]: Battle song" p. [6]: "[Beauty sequence]: Recit. Lovely lady," "[Not so innocent fun]: Girls to judge" p. [7]: "[His chances are not worth a penny]: Finaletto," "Westerners," "Southerners intro," "Farmers," "Society," "Indians" p. [8]: "[A] treaty, [my sweetie, with you]," "Indians" (continued from p. [7]) (Box-folder 8/34)
      - [Sketches for I'd Rather Be Right], Holograph sketch in pencil; [1] p.; Includes: "[I'd rather be right]: Verse" and several unidentified fragments (Box-folder 8/34)
    - If I Were King (1923) lyrics by Lorenz Hart
      - [The] band of the ne'er-do-wells, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil, no lyric; [4] p. (Box-folder 8/35)
      - Courtly etiquette, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil, no lyric; 7 p. (Box-folder 8/36)
      - Lady of heaven; Life is unstable, Holograph piano score and piano-vocal score in pencil, no lyrics; 2 p. (Box-folder 8/37)
      - Life is unstable see: Lady of heaven
      - Minuet, Holograph piano score in pencil; 3 p. (Box-folder 8/38)
      - Minuett, Manuscript piano score in pencil & ink; [2] p. (Box-folder 8/38)
      - Opening act I, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil, no lyric; 4 p. (Box-folder 8/39)
      - Waltz, Ms. piano score in ink; [2] p. (Box-folder 8/40)
    - Jumbo (1935; film 1962) lyrics by Lorenz Hart
      - The circus is on parade, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 6 p. (Box-folder 9/1)
      - Finale act II: wedding, Holograph condensed score sketch in pencil; 7 p.; Uniform title: The circus wedding (Box-folder 9/2)
      - Diavolo, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 7 p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet; p. 8-9 (Box-folder 9/3)
      - Ist act finale waltz; Intro to wire walkers, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil, no lyric; [4] p.; At end: "Segue to Newer Waltz"; Uniform title: Finale act 1 (Box-folder 9/4)
      - Newer waltz: finale act I, Holograph piano score in pencil; [2] p.; Uniform title: Finale act 1 (Box-folder 9/4)
      - Finale act I: box and white horse march, Holograph piano score in pencil; [2] p.; Note: White horse march section headed "March (White Horse)"; Uniform title: Finale act 1 (Box-folder 9/4)
      - Act I finale: Foster girls, Holograph piano score in pencil; [1] p.; Uniform title: Finale act 1 (Box-folder 9/4)
      - Giant calliope: finale act II, Holograph piano score in pencil; [1] p. (Box-folder 9/5)
      - Laugh see: [Sketches for Jumbo]
      - Little girl blue, Holograph piano-vocal score and piano score, in pencil; 7 p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet; p. 6 (Box-folder 9/6)
      - March of the clowns: also March of animals, Holograph condensed score in pencil; 8 p.; Laid in: holograph piano score in ink of transition for optional cut; [1] p. (Box-folder 9/7)
      - Memories of Madison Square Garden see: [Sketches for Jumbo]
      - The more I see of other girls: elephant song See also: [Sketches for Mississippi], Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [3] p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet, crossed out annotations in pencil; [1] p. (Box-folder 9/8)
      - The most beautiful girl in the world, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 8 p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheets for verse and chorus, annotations in pencil; [2] p. (Box-folder 9/9)
      - My romance, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [3] p. (Box-folder 9/10)
      - New strain for [Kimris?], Holograph piano score in pencil; [1] p.; At end: melodic fragment for "2nd strain of Clown March" (Box-folder 9/11)
      - Over and over again see: [Sketches for Jumbo]
      - The song of the roustabouts see: [Sketches for Jumbo]
      - There's a small hotel see: [M.S. 9] in MISCELLANEOUS SKETCHES
      - Women!, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 6 p. (Box-folder 9/12)
      - [Sketches for Jumbo], Holograph sketches in pencil; [14] p.; Includes: p. [2]: "[Over and over again]: Patter Jumbo opening," "[Little girl blue]: Verse Blue day" p. [3]: "Barnum & Bailey" p. [4]: "You who are lovely" p. [5]: "[Memories of Madison Square Garden]: Barnum I," "Barnum II" p. [6]: "Diavolo: [verse & intro]" p. [7]: "[The circus is on parade]: Circus march," "Diavolo" p. [9]: "Spring song," "[The song of the roustabouts]" p. [10]: "Women?" p. [11]: "Laugh," "[Glad to be unhappy]" (from On Your Toes) p. [12]: "[The song of the roustabouts]: No job in Omaha" p. [13]: "Women?" (Box-folder 9/13)
      - [Sketches for Jumbo], Photocopy of holograph sketches; [4] p.; Includes: p. [1]: "Verse [The most beautiful] girl in the world," "Women?" p. [4]: "[There's a] small hotel" (cut from Jumbo but used in On Your Toes), "Verse Love you more [tomorrow?]" (Box-folder 9/13)
      - [Sketches for Jumbo], Holograph sketches in pencil; [4] p.; Includes: p. [1]: "[The circus is on parade]: March," "March" p. [2]: "Trio of presto," "Verse presto" p. [3]: "[Hoctor?] waltz," "Chee-chee" p. [4]: "March," "[The] circus [is on parade]" (Box-folder 9/13)
      - [Sketches for Jumbo], Holograph sketches in pencil; [2] p.; Includes: p. [1]: "[It's got to be love]" (from On Your Toes), "[There's a] small hotel: verse & patter" (cut from Jumbo but used in On Your Toes) p. [2]: "[My romance]" (Box-folder 9/13)
      - [Sketches for Jumbo], Holograph sketches in pencil; [1] p.; Includes: "[The most beautiful girl in the world]" and unidentified (Box-folder 9/13)
    - June Days (1925) lyrics by Lorenz Hart
      - Anyway, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil, no lyric; [3] p.; Uniform title: Anytime, anywhere, anyhow (Box-folder 9/14)
    - Keep 'Em Rolling (1942), film short, lyric by Lorenz Hart
      - Keep 'em rolling!, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [6] p. (Box-folder 9/15)
    - The King and I (1951; film 1956) lyrics by Oscar Hammerstein II
      - Anna's bedroom, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 8 p.; Typed lyric sheet, annotations in pencil; 3 p. (Box-folder 9/16)
      - Getting to know you See also: [Sketches for South Pacific], Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [3] p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet; [1] p. (Box-folder 9/17)
      - Hello, young lovers, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 5 p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet, annotations in pencil; [1] p. (Box-folder 9/18)
      - Anna and son Klin scene: leading to Hello, young lovers song, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [4] p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet, annotations in pencil; [1] p. (Box-folder 9/18)
      - Before verse of Hello young lovers, Holograph piano-vocal sketch in pencil; 3 p. (Box-folder 9/18)
      - I have dreamed, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [3] p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet, annotations in pencil; [1] p. (Box-folder 9/19)
      - I have dreamed, Holograph sketch in pencil; [2] p.; Note: includes unidentified sketch material at top of p. [1] (Box-folder 9/19)
      - I whistle a happy tune, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [4] p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet; [1] p. (Box-folder 9/20)
      - Kralahome, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [2] p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet; [1] p. (Box-folder 9/21)
      - Children's march, Holograph piano score in pencil; [2] p.; Uniform title: March of the royal Siamese children (Box-folder 9/22)
      - March?, Holograph sketch/piano score in pencil; [3] p.; On back: unidentified holograph sketch material; Uniform title: March of the royal Siamese children (Box-folder 9/22)
      - [My] lord and master, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [4] p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet, annotation in pencil; [1] p. (Box-folder 9/23)
      - Now you leave, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [3] p. (Box-folder 9/24)
      - [A] puzzlement, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 9 p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet; [2] p. (Box-folder 9/25)
      - [A] puzzlement, Holograph piano-vocal sketch in pencil, partial lyric; [4] p. (Box-folder 9/25)
      - [The Royal Bangkok Academy], Holograph sketch in pencil with lyric; [1] p.; Typed lyric sheet; [1] p. (Box-folder 9/26)
      - Shall we dance?, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [3] p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet; [1] p. (Box-folder 9/27)
      - Something wonderful, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [4] p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet; [1] p. (Box-folder 9/28)
      - He can be wonderful, Holograph sketch in pencil with lyric; [2] p. (Box-folder 9/28)
      - [Song of the] king, Holograph piano-vocal score/sketch in pencil; [3] p.; Laid in: portion of typed script which includes lyric of "Song of the king"; [2] p. (Box-folder 9/29)
      - Waiting, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [8] p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet, annotations in pencil; [3] p. (Box-folder 9/30)
      - We kiss in a shadow, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [3] p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet, annotations in pencil; [1] p. (Box-folder 9/31)
      - Opening act 2, Ms. piano-vocal score in pencil; [4] p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet, annotations in pencil; [1] p.; Uniform title: Western people funny (Box-folder 9/32)
      - Why? Why? Why?, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [4] p.; Laid in: portion of the typed script which includes lyric for "Why? Why? Why?," annotations in pencil, including melodic and rhythmic notations; [5] p. (Box-folder 9/33)
      - Why? Why? Why?: new development, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [2] p.; Note: laid in as part of above piano-vocal score (Box-folder 9/33)
      - Incidentals for dialogues, Holograph incidental music (melody lines) with dialogue, in pencil; [2] p. (Box-folder 9/34)
      - [Sketches for The King and I], Holograph sketches in pencil; [8] p.; Includes: p. [1]: Argument song p. [2]: [My] lord and master p. [3]: [I whistle a] happy tune p. [4]: [My] lord and master p. [5]: Argument song contd. p. [6]: [We] kiss in a shadow p. [7]: Hello, young lovers p. [8]: [We] kiss in a shadow (Box-folder 9/35)
      - [Program]: Printed program of the National Theater production, Washington, D.C., August 29, 1955. (Box-folder 9/36)
    - Lady Fingers (1929) lyrics by Lorenz Hart
      - I love you more than yesterday see: [M.S. 2] in MISCELLANEOUS SKETCHES
    - Lawrence of Arabia (ca. 1960) unproduced [probably a television documentary]
      - Arab friend: counter to "Lawrence theme", Holograph condensed score in pencil, no lyric; [3] p. (Box-folder 10/1)
      - Arab military, Holograph condensed score in pencil, no lyric; 2 p. (Box-folder 10/2)
      - Arab military: lyrical, Holograph condensed score in pencil, no lyric; [2] p. (Box-folder 10/2)
      - British military & music hall, Holograph condensed score in pencil, no lyric; [2] p. (Box-folder 10/3)
      - [The father of the bride?], Holograph piano-vocal sketch in pencil, lyricist unknown; [1] p. (Box-folder 10/4)
      - Lawrence theme: counter to "Arab friend", Holograph condensed score in pencil, no lyric; [3] p. (Box-folder 10/5)
      - Michener, Holograph piano score/condensed score in pencil; 4 p. (incomplete) (Box-folder 10/6)
      - [Sketches for Lawrence of Arabia], Holograph sketches in pencil; [5] p. + blanks; Includes: "Lawrence of Arabia" "[Unidentified]" (Box-folder 10/7)
    - Let's Have Fun (1935) radio musical comedy
      - I'll take a little of you on toast see: [M.S. 8] in MISCELLANEOUS SKETCHES
      - Please make me be good see: [M.S. 8] in MISCELLANEOUS SKETCHES
    - Lido Lady (1926) lyrics by Lorenz Hart
      - Atlantic blues See also: [M.S. 3] in MISCELLANEOUS SKETCHES, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil, no lyric; [3] p.; Note: same music as "Blue ocean blues" of Present Arms (Box-folder 10/8)
      - [The] beauty of another day See also: [M.S. 3] in MISCELLANEOUS SKETCHES, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil, no lyric; [4] p. (Box-folder 10/9)
      - Chuck it! see: [M.S. 3] in MISCELLANEOUS SKETCHES see: Chuck it! in Peggy-Ann
      - A cup of tea see: [M.S. 3] in MISCELLANEOUS SKETCHES
      - Ever-ready Freddy See also: [M.S. 3] in MISCELLANEOUS SKETCHES, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil, no lyric; [4] p. (Box-folder 10/10)
      - Exercise, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil, no lyric; [3] p. (Box-folder 10/11)
      - Finale act two See also: [M.S. 3] in MISCELLANEOUS SKETCHES, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil, no lyric; 8 p.; Note: includes chorus of "Here in my arms" (Box-folder 10/12)
      - I want a man, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil, no lyric; [3] p. (Box-folder 10/13)
      - Lido lady see: [M.S. 3] in MISCELLANEOUS SKETCHES
      - Morning is midnight see: [M.S. 3] in MISCELLANEOUS SKETCHES
      - My heart is Sheba bound see: [M.S. 3] in MISCELLANEOUS SKETCHES
      - A little flat in Soho See also: [M.S. 3] in MISCELLANEOUS SKETCHES, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil, no lyric; [4] p.; Note: same music as "A little house in Soho" from She's My Baby; Uniform title: A tiny flat near Soho Square (Box-folder 10/14)
      - Try again tomorrow see: [M.S. 3] in MISCELLANEOUS SKETCHES
      - Two to eleven See also: [M.S. 3] in MISCELLANEOUS SKETCHES, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil, no lyric; [4] p. (Box-folder 10/15)
      - You're on the Lido now see: [M.S. 3] in MISCELLANEOUS SKETCHES
    - Love Me Tonight (1932) film, lyrics by Lorenz Hart
      - Isn't it romantic? See also: [M.S. 6] in MISCELLANEOUS SKETCHES, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil, partial lyric; [5] p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet, annotations in pencil; [3] p. (Box-folder 10/16)
      - Love me tonight, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil, no lyric; [3] p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet; [1] p. (Box-folder 10/17)
      - Lover!, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil, no lyric; [3] p.; Typed lyric sheet with title in pencil; [1] p.; Note: original title, "Song to an illegitimate horse," crossed out (Box-folder 10/18)
      - The man for me, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil, partial lyric; 4 p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet, annotations in pencil; 3 p. (Box-folder 10/19)
      - Mimi, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil, no lyric; [3] p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet, annotations in pencil; [1] p. (Box-folder 10/20)
      - Pierrot, Holograph sketch in ink; [1] p.; Note: seems related to "Isn't it romantic" (Box-folder 10/21)
      - The poor Apache, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil, no lyric; 7 p.; Typed lyric sheet, title in pencil; [2] p.; Note: lyric's original title, "I'm an Apache," crossed out (Box-folder 10/22)
      - The son-of-a-gun is nothing but a tailor!, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil, no lyric; 9 p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet; 2 p. (Box-folder 10/23)
      - [That's] the song of Paree, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 10 p. (Box-folder 10/24)
      - A woman needs something like that, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 11 p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet, annotations in pencil; 4 p. (Box-folder 10/25)
    - Main Street to Broadway (1953) film
      - There's music in you, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [4] p.; Lyric by Oscar Hammerstein II; Laid in: typed lyric sheet titled "Music in you"; 2 p. (Box-folder 10/26)
    - Me and Juliet (1953) lyrics by Oscar Hammerstein II
      - The baby you love see: Me and Juliet sequence see: [Sketches for Me and Juliet]
      - The big black giant, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 5 p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet; [1] p. (Box-folder 10/27)
      - I'm your girl, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [2] p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet; [1] p. (Box-folder 10/28)
      - Verse -- I'm your girl, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [1] p. (Box-folder 10/28)
      - Ten minutes' intermission, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 16 p.; Uniform title: Intermission talk (Box-folder 10/29)
      - It feels good, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 6 p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheets (2), annotations in pencil; [1] p. each (Box-folder 10/30)
      - It's me, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 4 p. (Box-folder 10/31)
      - Keep it gay, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [4] p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet; [1] p. (Box-folder 10/32)
      - Marriage type love, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [4] p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet; [1] p. (Box-folder 10/33)
      - Marriage type love, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [2] p. (Box-folder 10/33)
      - Me and Juliet sequence: act II, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 12 p.; Includes: "You're not living" (which is "The baby you love") "Meat and potatoes" (Box-folder 10/34)
      - Opening of Me and Juliet See also: [Sketches for Me and Juliet], p. [15]: "My bounty" See also: [Sketches for Me and Juliet], p. [16]: "Me, who am I?", Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [8] p.; Note: includes sections marked "Me, who am I?" and "My bounty"; Laid in: typed lyric sheet; [2] p.; Laid in: typed script including lyrics, annotations in ink & pencil; [5] p. (Box-folder 10/35)
      - That's the way it happens, Typed lyric sheet; [1] p. (Box-folder 10/36)
      - That's the way it happens, Typed script including lyrics, annotations in pencil; [4] p. (Box-folder 10/36)
      - A very special day, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [2] p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheets (4) in two slightly different versions, annotations in pencil on one lyric sheet; [1] p. each (Box-folder 10/37)
      - Verse: Special day, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [1] p. (Box-folder 10/37)
      - Wake up little theatre, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 5 p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet; [1] p. (Box-folder 10/38)
      - [Sketches for Me and Juliet], Holograph sketches in pencil; [21] p.; Includes: p. [1]: "[That's the way it happens]: Girl from Chicago" p. [2-3]: "Wake up little theatre" p. [4]: "[A very special day]: I'm a girl" p. [5]: "It feels good" p. [6]: "It's me" p. [7]: "It feels good" p. [9]: "Keep it gay" p. [10-11]: "Marriage type [love]" p. [12]: "X-mas" p. [13]: "March" p. [14]: "Never had it so good," "[The big black] giant" p. [15]: "My bounty", "Verse Marriage type [love]" p. [16]: "Juliet," "Me, who am I?" p. [17]: "[The big black] giant" p. [18]: "Nothin' for nothin'" p. [19]: "Marrying kind," "Marriage type love" p. [20]: "[Marriage type love]" p. [21]: "Nothin' for nothin'," "[The] baby [you love]" (same as "You're not living" of "Me and Juliet sequence") (Box-folder 10/39)
    - The Melody Man (1924; film 1930) comedy by Herbert Fields, R. Rodgers, and Lorenz Hart
      - Moonlight Mama, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil, no lyric; [2] p.; Note: song credited to "Herbert Richard Lorenz" (pseudonym for Herbert Fields, Richard Rodgers and Lorenz Hart) (Box-folder 11/1)
    - Mississippi (1935) musical film, lyrics by Lorenz Hart
      - Easy to remember see: [M.S. 8] in MISCELLANEOUS SKETCHES
      - I keep on singing, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [3] p.; Laid in: typed lyric sheet; [1] p. (Box-folder 11/2)
      - [Sketches for Mississippi], Holograph sketches in pencil; [4] p.; Includes: p. [1]: "Verse Mississippi" p. [2]: "[I keep on singing]" p. [3]: "[The more I see of other girls]", or, "[The elephant song]" (cut from Jumbo) p. [4]: "[Down by the river]" (Box-folder 11/3)
    - No Strings (1962) lyrics by Richard Rodgers
      - Be my host, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; [4] p. (Box-folder 11/4)
      - Verse Be my host; Be my host, Holograph sketch in pencil; [2] p.; On p. [2]: crossed out unidentified holograph sketch material (Box-folder 11/4)
      - Eager beaver, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 7 p. (Box-folder 11/5)
      - Eager beaver, Holograph sketch in pencil, partial lyric; [2] p. (Box-folder 11/5)
      - How sad, Holograph piano-vocal score in pencil; 7 p.; Note: holograph sketch material for "How sad" on p. [8] (Box-folder 11/6)
      - [How sad], Holograph lyric sketch in pencil; [1] p. (Box-folder 11/6)
      - I was there, Holograph sketch in pencil; [1] p.; On t.p.: "1961 No Strings" (Box-folder 11/7)
      - [I was there], Holograph lyric sketches in pencil; [2] p. (Box-folder 11/7)